<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">About the World</string>
    <string name="pilih_gambar">(Select image to open gallery)</string>
    <string name="daftar_topik_berita">" Latest News List"</string>
    <string name="energi">Energy</string>
    <string name="energi_list_title">" Energy News List"</string>
    <string name="keajaiban_dunia">Wonder</string>
    <string name="keajaiban_list_title">List of Miracle News</string>
    <string name="pemimpin_negara">" Leader"</string>
    <string name="pemimpin_list_title">News List Leader</string>
    <string name="tokoh_teknologi">Figure</string>
    <string name="tokoh_list_title">List of News Characters</string>
    <string name="biomassa_nama">Biomass</string>
    <string name="biomassa_asal">Newly living plants and organisms</string>
    <string name="biomassa_bio">Bioenergy is a type of renewable energy that comes from biomass. Biomass is organic material derived from newly living plants and organisms. Using wood in your fireplace is an example of biomass that most people are familiar with.</string>
    <string name="hidroelektrik_nama">hydroelectric</string>
    <string name="hidroelektrik_asal">Water flowing through the dam turbine</string>
    <string name="hidroelektrik_bio">Dams are what most people associate with hydropower. Water flows through the dam\'s turbines to generate electricity, which is known as a hydropower storage pump. Stream hydropower uses channels to carry water rather than flowing it through dams.</string>
    <string name="hidrogen_nama">Hydrogen</string>
    <string name="hidrogen_asal">hydrogen gas</string>
    <string name="hidrogen_bio">Hydrogen needs to be combined with other elements, such as oxygen to make water because it doesn\'t occur naturally as a gas by itself. When hydrogen is separated from other elements, it can be used for fuel and electricity.</string>
    <string name="tenaga_surya_nama">Solar</string>
    <string name="tenaga_surya_asal">Sun</string>
    <string name="tenaga_surya_bio">This type of renewable energy is obtained by capturing radiant energy from sunlight and converting it into heat, electricity, or hot water. Photovoltaic (PV) systems can convert sunlight directly into electricity through the use of solar cells.</string>
    <string name="panas_bumi_nama">Geothermal</string>
    <string name="panas_bumi_asal">Natural gas</string>
    <string name="panas_bumi_bio">Geothermal heat is trapped beneath the earth\'s crust from the formation of the earth 4.5 billion years ago and from radioactive decay. Sometimes large amounts of this heat escape naturally, but all at once, produce familiar events, such as volcanic eruptions and geysers.</string>
    <string name="turbin_nama">Turbine or Propeller</string>
    <string name="turbin_asal">Wind</string>
    <string name="turbin_bio">Wind farms capture wind energy using turbines and convert it into electricity. Commercial grade wind generation systems can power many different organizations, while a single wind turbine is used to help complement a pre-existing energy organization.</string>
    <string name="borobudur_nama">Borobudur temple</string>
    <string name="borobudur_asal">Indonesia</string>
    <string name="borobudur_bio">Launching the Borobudur Park page, Borobudur Temple is a historical building left by the Syailendra Dynasty from 780 to 840 AD. The temple which is a UNESCO Cultural Heritage Site is also the largest Buddhist heritage in the world.</string>
    <string name="colosseum_nama">Colosseum</string>
    <string name="colosseum_asal">Italy</string>
    <string name="colosseum_bio">The Colosseum was once used as a venue for gladiatorial performances, humans dueling beasts. The Colosseum was also a place to watch chariot races and other duels during the Roman Empire. The show was entertainment for Emperor Vespasian.</string>
    <string name="kabah_nama">Kaaba</string>
    <string name="kabah_asal">Saudi Arabia</string>
    <string name="kabah_bio">The Kaaba is in the middle of the Grand Mosque and is the direction that Muslims face when praying. Kaaba in Arabic means cube. This sacred building is indeed square in shape and is draped with silk and layers of cotton. Muslims believe that the Kaaba was built by Prophet Ibrahim and his son Prophet Ismail.</string>
    <string name="menara_pisa_nama">Tower of Pissa</string>
    <string name="menara_pisa_asal">Italy</string>
    <string name="menara_pisa_bio">The Tower of Pisa is unique because its shape, which was built from the start, was never upright.</string>
    <string name="tajmahal_nama">Taj Mahal</string>
    <string name="tajmahal_asal">India</string>
    <string name="tajmahal_bio">The Taj Mahal is a monument in Agra, India, which previously had the name of a woman, namely Arjumand Banu Begum. This woman was nicknamed Mumtaz Mahal, which in turn became the forerunner to the name Taj Mahal.</string>
    <string name="tembok_cina_nama">Great Wall of China</string>
    <string name="tembok_cina_asal">China</string>
    <string name="tembok_cina_bio">The Great Wall of China is the longest wall ever in the world with ancient architecture. This wall has existed since 2,300 years ago and was built in different places to protect territorial lines. The Four Dynasties of China have contributed to the establishment of the giant wall which also served to prevent enemy attacks and the silk trade route in ancient times.</string>
    <string name="jokowi_nama">Joko Widodo</string>
    <string name="jokowi_asal">Joko Widodo</string>
    <string name="jokowi_bio">Ir. H. Joko Widodo DK (born June 21, 1961), or more familiarly called Jokowi, is the President of Indonesia who has been in office since October 20, 2014. Elected in the 2014 Presidential Election, Jokowi became the first President of Indonesia in history who did not come from an elite background. Indonesian politics or military. He was elected with Vice President Muhammad Jusuf Kalla and was re-elected with Vice President Maruf Amin in the 2019 Presidential Election.</string>
    <string name="kim_jong_nama">Kim Jong-un</string>
    <string name="kim_jong_asal">North Korea</string>
    <string name="kim_jong_bio">Kim Jong un (born January 8, 1983) is the Supreme Leader of the Democratic People\'s Republic of Korea, also known as North Korea. He is the son of Kim Jong il and the grandson of Kim Il sung. Prior to becoming the leader of North Korea, he served as First Secretary of the Workers\' Party of Korea, First Chairman of the Central Military Commission, Supreme Commander of the Korean People\'s Army, and Politburo of the Workers\' Party of Korea.</string>
    <string name="salman_nama">King Salman</string>
    <string name="salman_asal">Saudi Arabia</string>
    <string name="salman_bio">Salman bin Abdulaziz al Saud (born 31 December 1935) is the seventh King of Saudi Arabia, Custodian of the Two Holy Cities, and the current leader of the House of Saud. He served as Deputy Governor and then Governor of Riyadh for 48 years from 1963 to 2011. Salman was appointed King of Saudi Arabia on 23 January 2015 following the death of his half-brother, King Abdullah.</string>
    <string name="vladimir_nama">Vladimir Putin</string>
    <string name="vladimir_asal">Russia</string>
    <string name="vladimir_bio">Vladimir Vladimirovich Putin, (born 7 October 1952) is a Russian politician, and is the current President of Russia. He is the president with the second longest term in Europe after Alexander Lukashenko who is President of Belarus. Putin has been President of Russia since May 7, 2012.</string>
    <string name="erdogan_nama">Recep Tayyip Erdogan</string>
    <string name="erdogan_asal">Turkey</string>
    <string name="erdogan_bio">Recep Tayyip Erdogan (born 26 February 1954) is a Turkish politician who has served as President of Turkey since 2014. Previously, he served as Prime Minister of Turkey from 14 March 2003 to 28 August 2014. He is also a leader of the Adalet ve Kalkinma Partisi (AKP, or Party). Justice and Development). In 2010, Erdoan was voted the 2nd most influential Muslim figure in the world.</string>
    <string name="biden_nama">Joe Biden</string>
    <string name="biden_asal">United States of America</string>
    <string name="biden_bio">Joseph Robinette Biden Jr. (born November 20, 1942) is an American politician who served as the 46th President of the United States. After defeating his rival Donald Trump in the 2020 United States Presidential election, he was sworn in as the 46th President of the United States on January 20, 2021. He is a member of the Party Democrat and served as the 47th Vice President of the United States from 2009 to 2017 and a senior Senator from Delaware from 1973 to 2009.</string>
    <string name="elon_musk_nama">Elon Musk</string>
    <string name="elon_musk_asal">United States of America</string>
    <string name="elon_musk_bio">Elon Reeve Musk FRS (born June 28, 1971) is an American businessman, inventor, and industrialist. He is the founder and CEO of SpaceX, CEO and production engineer for Tesla, founder of The Boring Company, and founder of Neuralink.</string>
    <string name="jackma_nama">Jack Ma</string>
    <string name="jackma_asal">China</string>
    <string name="jackma_bio">Jack Ma (born September 10, 1964) is a Chinese businessman. He is the founder and Executive Chairman of Alibaba Group, the largest e-commerce company in China. He is the first Mainland Chinese citizen to ever appear in Forbes magazine and is listed as a world billionaire. In 2015, he entered the list of the most influential people in the world at number 22. Jack Ma officially resigned from Alibaba\'s board of directors on September 30, 2019.</string>
    <string name="jef_bezos_nama">Jeff Bezos</string>
    <string name="jef_bezos_asal">United States of America</string>
    <string name="jef_bezos_bio">Jeffrey Preston Bezos (born January 12, 1964) is the world\'s richest businessman in modern history. He is the founder, chairman, CEO, president and majority owner of the world\'s largest technology company Amazon.com. A graduate of Princeton University, Bezos was a member of Phi Beta Kappa, working as a financial analyst for D. E. Shaw and Co. before founding Amazon in 1994. He was voted Person of the Year by TIME magazine.</string>
    <string name="zuck_nama">Mark Zuckerberg</string>
    <string name="zuck_asal">United States of America</string>
    <string name="zuck_bio">Mark Elliot Zuckerberg (born May 14, 1984) is a computer programmer and Internet entrepreneur. He is known for creating the social networking site Facebook. Facebook was founded as a private company in 2004 by Zuckerberg and his classmates Dustin Moskovitz, Eduardo Saverin, and Chris Hughes while students at Harvard University.</string>
    <string name="sundar_pichai_nama">Sundar Pichai</string>
    <string name="sundar_pichai_asal">India</string>
    <string name="sundar_pichai_bio">Pichai Sundarajan, better known as Sundar Pichai (born 12 July 1972), is the Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of Alphabet Inc. and its subsidiary, Google. Pichai joined Google in 2004, where he served as head of product management and innovation of Google\'s client software, including Google Chrome, Chrome OS, and Google Drive. He is also responsible for developing applications such as Gmail and Google Maps.</string>
    <string name="tim_cook_nama">Tim Cook</string>
    <string name="tim_cook_asal">United States of America</string>
    <string name="tim_cook_bio">Timothy Donald Cook (born November 1, 1960) is the chief executive officer (CEO) of the multimedia company Apple Inc. He has worked at Apple since 1998. His main job is managing the day-to-day operations of the company. He became CEO after Steve Jobs stepped down from the position on August 24, 2011.</string>
    <string name="profile">STUDENT PROFILE</string>
    <string name="nama">Name</string>
    <string name="aziz">: Muhammad Malik Aziz Al Kutbi</string>
    <string name="nim">NIM</string>
    <string name="prodi">Study Program</string>
    <string name="ti">: Technical Information</string>
    <string name="kls">Class</string>
    <string name="mk">MK</string>
    <string name="promile">: Mobile Programming</string>
    <string name="smstr">Semester</string>
    <string name="tiga">: 3 (Three)</string>
    <string name="hoby">Hobby</string>
    <string name="olahraga">: Sports, Reading, Learning to Coding</string>
    <string name="tekan">(Press image to open gallery)</string>
    <string name="go_back">Return</string>
</resources>